PASCAL JARDIN

FRONT END DEVELOPER | BACK END DEVELOPER | IOS/ANDROID DEVELOPER

858-472-9511 | pjardin@me.com | Poway, CA 92064 www.github.com/pjardin | www.pascaljardin.com | www.linkedin.com/in/PascalJardin/

SUMMARY AND KEY SKILLS

Collaborative, motivated, and solution-driven Computer Scientist with successful experience working in remote, distributed, global, and fast-paced environments. A second-generation computer scientist with comprehensive experience in research and development. Excited to utilize current technical knowledge and quick learning mindset to create a significant impact. Demonstrated strong communication skills and reputed as an exceptional problem solver, organizer and advocate, working with teams toward shared goals and objectives.

TECHNOLOGIES

Google Drive (Docs, Sheets, Slides), Microsoft Office (Word, Excel, PowerPoint), Dropbox, Zoom, Slack, Skype, JIRA, HomeBase, Postman, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Java, C++, OOP, C, C#, Objective-C, Swift, Android, iOS, GitHub, Git, SQL, MySQL, PSQL, Computer Vision, Augmented Reality (AR), Virtual Reality (VR), Open CV, dlib, bash, Linux, command line, VIM, APIs, AWS, AWS Lambda, AWS DynamoDB, Blender, 3d Animation, 3D Graphics, Unity, Reasct.js, SCSS.js, Node.js, Oodo.sh, jQuery, Visual Studio, Android Studio, XCode, Eclipse, Postman, Ruby, Python, Git, SQL Server, PostgreSQL, MySQL, Access, ReSharper, Visual Studio, Visual Studio Code, FilemakerPro, Mailchimp, CushyCMS, PHP, Linux OS, Windows OS, Mac OS

EDUCATION AND RELEVANT COURSEWORK

Bachelor of Science (BS) | Computer Science, California State University, San Marcos California

5/2020

Graduated with Magna Cum Laude, high honors, GPA 3.713

Machine Learning Systems | Introduction to Mobile Programming | Game Programming

EXPERIENCE

Instructor | Fully Remote | Part Time | Virtual, Home-Based Office, Poway, California Delaware STEAM Academy, Newark, DE

7/2020 - Present

Teaching 4 to 12 students a class Python and JavaScript ages 8 to 16 years old.

Blender Artist | Fully Remote | Internship | Virtual, Home-Based Office, Poway, California Kana's Island, Las Angeles, CA

6/2020 - 8/2020

- - Internship under the Disney Imagineer Mark page
 - Retopology and game ready characters.
 - Created entire teaser https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=2vS6z80gOUY
 - Created figurines
 - Lighting, rigging, modeling, animation, sound and VFX

Front End Developer | Fully Remote | Virtual, Home-Based Office, Poway, California

5/2020 - 6/2020

Bluemark, Valencia, CA

- Work on a 5-member team as a Front End Developer developing a react portal for users in shipping items
- Execute application development within very tight time constraints within a one week, sprint period
- Collaborate and complete back end development work with odoo.sh as needed due to the strict deadlines
- Process tickets logged through JIRA while communicating with team members regularly through Slack and logging in with HomeBase
- Successfully doubled the website loading speed and tripled the performance by storing data into a cache

AWS developer | Full Stack Engineer | Blender Artist | Freelancer | Fully Remote

5/2020 - 6/2020

LadyJustice.us, San Marcos, CA

- Designed, developed, and hosted https://ladyjustice.us.
- Hosted on AWS through rout 53 and s3 bucket.
- Secured website using AWS cloud front
- Created multiple videos using Blender, can be found on site.

AWS developer | Full Stack Engineer | Freelancer

5/2020 - 5/2020

Violet Health, Poway, CA

- Designed, developed, and hosted a website called http://violet.health for a startup company.
- Hosted on AWS through rout 53 and s3 bucket.

Instructor/Teacher 1/2020 – 5/2020

The Coder School, San Diego, CA

- Develop individualized and targeted curriculums for each student to aide them in achieving coding education goals
- Instruct, mentor, and coach students on coding languages as a "Coder Coach", Python, Java, HTML, and JavaScript, as well as coding tools such as Blender and Unity

AWS developer | Full Stack Engineer | Back End Developer | Freelancer

8/2019 - 12/2019

Reciposts, San Marcos, CA

- Designed, developed, and hosted a fully functional social media platform called https://reciposts.com.
- Hosted on AWS through rout 53 and s3 bucket.
- Secured website using AWS cloud front
- Back end using Node.js lambda serverless function using AWS Gateway.

Full Stack Engineer | Fully Remote | Virtual, Home-Based Office, Poway, California

11/2018 - 01/2019

Graffiti Artist, Stockholm, Sweden

- Partnered with professional graffiti artist and owner of MindGem Graphics on developing and launching internet/social media presence through creation of http://graffiticreator.net utilizing iMessage Graffiti creator app, https://apps.apple.com/us/app/graffiti-creator-stickers/id1449321346?ls=1
- Created a webpage capable of drawing graffiti letters through the use of HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and jQuery and integrated it into the iMessage app to pull a WebView to display the website
- Enabled viewing of the webpage via the app through utilization of XCode and swift
- Published the app via the iTunes app store, http://itunesconnect.apple.com

Web Developer 02/2017 – 05/2018

Kokua Botanicals, San Marcos, CA

 Designed and developed a website using Wix focused discussing nasal health benefits and reduced inflammation https://wajardin.wixsite.com/mysite

3D Printer Technician 03/2016 – 08/2017

AccendoWave, Poway, CA

Created a magnetic charging station for tables and EEG headbands for AccendoWave. Executed the 3D printing of
parts with a Maker Bot printer and incorporated Blender in designing the magnate charging station pieces and
design, https://www.accendowave.com

Research and Development Engineer | Flexible Schedule

08/2014 - 01/2020

JardinLabs, Poway, CA

• Designed and created a Patent web scrapper to search/scrap all patents and store in a database for a patent firm; resulting in the patent firm's ability to search for copyright infringements

- Crafted front end and back end design development for PopTagz, an augmented reality graffiti app allowing the
 user to tag in a virtual reality space; Utilized web apps and Swift to gather user GPS locations and pulled content
 from an AWS sever, apps.apple.com/us/app/poptagz/id1265471660?ls=1
- Participated in the Shielded research project to develop VR EEG headset for network security; wrote Unity code
 in C# to display content to users and implemented sockets between open BCI, allowing for brain data and
 raspberry pi data to be sent to Amazon servers for data processing
- Wrote socket code connecting "the frame" of a project to an Amazon s3 bucket utilized in the Forget Me Not research project focused on stimulating memory abilities